<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A true declaration of the streight siedge laide to the cytty of Steenwich and of the skirmishes and battailes which happened on both sides, very strange and aduenturous. Heerevnto is also annexed, in what maner the enemie besought to parley with Counte Maurice his excellency, conserning the yeelding vp of the citty into his hands. Togither with the yeelding vp of the same. Printed in Dutch, and translated into English, by I.T[horius].</title>
            <title>Warachtighe beschryvinge von de sware belegeringhe der stadt Steenwijck. English.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1592</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 13 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 7 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A12949</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 23241</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S101972</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99837775</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99837775</idno>
            <idno type="VID">2117</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A12949)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 2117)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 1035:12)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A true declaration of the streight siedge laide to the cytty of Steenwich and of the skirmishes and battailes which happened on both sides, very strange and aduenturous. Heerevnto is also annexed, in what maner the enemie besought to parley with Counte Maurice his excellency, conserning the yeelding vp of the citty into his hands. Togither with the yeelding vp of the same. Printed in Dutch, and translated into English, by I.T[horius].</title>
                  <title>Warachtighe beschryvinge von de sware belegeringhe der stadt Steenwijck. English.</title>
                  <author>Thorie, John, b. 1568.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[4], 8 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by John Wolfe, and are to be solde at his shop, right ouer against the great south doore of Paules,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1592.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Printer's device (McKerrow 251, shading from right to left) on title page.</note>
                  <note>Translator's name conjectured by STC.</note>
                  <note>A translation, perhaps by John Thorie, of Warachtighe beschryvinge von de sware belegeringhe der stadt Steenwijck.</note>
                  <note>Print faded and show-through.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Netherlands --  History --  Wars of Independence, 1556-1648 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>[Steenwyjk (Netherlands) Siege, 1572] --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-12</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-12</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:2117:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 113 -->
            <pb facs="tcp:2117:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 113 -->
            <p>A TRVE DECLARA<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of the ſtreight ſiedge laide <hi>to the Cytty of Steenwich, and of the Skir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſhes</hi> and Battailes which happened on both ſides, very ſtrange and aduenturous.</p>
            <p>Heerevnto is alſo annexed, in what maner the Enemie beſought to parley with <hi>Counte Maurice</hi> his Excellency, conſerning the yeel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding vp of the Citty into his hands.</p>
            <p>Togither with the yeelding vp of the ſame.</p>
            <p>Printed firſt in Dutch, and truely tranſlated into Engliſh, by I.T.</p>
            <figure>
               <figDesc>fleur-de-lis</figDesc>
            </figure>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON</hi> 
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="5 letters">
                  <desc>•••••</desc>
               </gap>ed by Iohn Wolfe, and are to be ſolde <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> his ſhop, right ouer againſt the great South doore of Poules. 1592.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="translator_to_the_reader">
            <pb facs="tcp:2117:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 114 -->
            <pb facs="tcp:2117:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 114 -->
            <head>The Tranſlators Preface to <hi>the Reader.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">G</seg>Entle Reader, as you maye by this preſent declaration perceyue the miſeries and calamities which are dayly ſuffered in the Low-coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tries by the people there, ſo can you not but withall acknowledge how greatly you are bounden vnto almightie God for all the benefits wherewith it hath pleaſed his Diuine maieſtie ſo many yeares to bleſſe our countrie for theſe foure and thirtie yeares and more, what age hath ſeene a more happie eſtate than ours? What Nation hath had ſo well guided a gouernment as this? what people haue inioyed the free diſpoſing of themſelues and their goods more than we? what countrie vnder the vale of heauen hath bene more adorned with the enſignes of peace than England? O England! Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land! Peace hath bene thy bliſſe, Take heed it be not thy bane. For if through peace you become ſo put out of memory of warre, that the remembrance thereof is not able to put you in mind how ingratitude and wic<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kedneſſe
<pb facs="tcp:2117:3"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 115 -->will be puniſhed by warre, then vndoubtedly as you growe by Peace, ſo by Peace you ſhall fall. Wherefore let vs beſeech God of his mercie to giue vs grace to eſchew ſinne; the cauſe of warre and all miſerie, for ſo the cauſe being auoyded, the effect will take no place. Which God graunt for his glories ſake, and the good of all Chriſtian people.</p>
            <closer>
               <salute>Farewell.</salute>
            </closer>
            <trailer type="illustration">
               <figure>
                  <figDesc>Tudor rose</figDesc>
               </figure>
            </trailer>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:2117:3" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 115 -->
            <head>A True declaration of the ſiedge <hi>layde to the Cyttie of Steenwich, and of the</hi> Skirmiſhes and Battayles which happened on both ſides, very ſtrange and aduenterous.</head>
            <head type="sub">Heere is alſo annexed, in what manner the E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nimye beſought <hi>Count Maurice</hi> to parley with him, co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>cerning the condition of yeel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding vp the Citty into the hands of his Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cellencie.</head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">I</seg>T happened, that our No<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble Prince <hi>Count Maurice</hi> of <hi>Naſſaw</hi> Gouernor generall of the vnited Prouinces, &amp; the valiant Prince <hi>Count William</hi> gouernor of <hi>Frieſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land,</hi> hauing aſſembled a great power of men and ſouldiers, on horſſe &amp; foot, as well by ſea as by land, being wel pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uided of all kinde of munition appertaining to war, ioyned their forces togither and brought them before the Cittie of <hi>Steenwich,</hi> vppon the
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:2117:4" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 116 -->xxviii. day of May, being <hi>Corpus Chriſti</hi> day, a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bout nine of the clocke in the morning, where they beſieged the ſaid Cittie verye ſtraightlie and ſtrongly, parting their powers into foure Campes, and planting them in foure ſundrye places about the Cittie.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Parma</hi> had ſent into <hi>Steenwich</hi> ſixteen com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>panies, of all kind of Nations and people min<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gled togither, among which were diuers free<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>buyters and marchants, that had been dealers in the betrayeng and ſelling of <hi>Gertruynberch.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Alſo diuers others that had beene at <hi>Deuen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter,</hi> and had ſworne not to ſerue againſt <hi>Count Maurice</hi> in three yeares: with manye more that had reuolted from <hi>Count Maurice</hi> to the e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nimie, and for ſome crime or euill act commit<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ted, runne from their captaines to eſcape de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerued puniſhment.</p>
            <p>The Enimies ſeeing that they were ſo ſtrait<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly beſieged, the Maieſtrates and chiefe officers called all the Souldiers vnto them, where they all ſwore very ſolemnelie both Souldiers and Citizens to ſticke one to the other, and not to forſake one another, but to ſtande to the full triall of their fortune, and rather to die enerye man, then to yeelde to their enimy.</p>
            <p>Wherevpon they beganne to reſiſte the aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaultes which were by vs made vppon them and valiantlie to defend themſelues to the vt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>termoſt: inſomuch that in the very beginning
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:2117:4" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 116 -->they ſlewe and ſpoiled many pioners and En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gliſhmen.</p>
            <p>The fourth daye of Iune did they of <hi>Steen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wich</hi> make an iſſue vpon vs, at which time they ſlew many Engliſhmen, and the moſt parte of <hi>Olthofs</hi> ſouldiers, beſides many whome they wounded, and fiue whome they tooke Pryſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners, one of them be<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ng an Engliſhman, whom they hanged: but we draue them into the Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tie againe ſo ſpeedilie, that they were forced to ſhut out two of their ſouldiers, whome wee ſlew vnder the gates of the Citie.</p>
            <p>After this they planted their field peeces on the top of their towne houſe ſteeple, whence they ſhot ſtones, chaines, and iron barres, into our Campe, which much hurt our Souldiors: although we were told that they had but ſeuen Cannon ſhot in all.</p>
            <p>The ſixt day of Iune, <hi>Count Maurice,</hi> cauſed all the great ſhot to bee diſcharged vppon the Cittie, which made ſuch a terrible and fearfull noiſe, that the very earth ſemed to ſhake aboue three miles from the place: beginning at foure of the clocke in the morning and continueng till nine: inſomuch that there wer aboue four thouſande ſhottes diſplaied vppon the Cittye. But the rampire which our men had made, was ſomething to lowe, by reaſon whereof the bullets flew over the Citty into <hi>Counte Williams</hi> Campe, whereby we were compelled to ceaſe
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:2117:5" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 117 -->the play of the Cannon.</p>
            <p>After which ſtorme they of the Citie came with broomes to ſweepe the walles in a moo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kage, leaſt forſooth the duſt of the ſhot ſhould haue fouled the walles, making ſo light of the matter, as if they had no harme by the cannon that had ſo furiouſlye barked at them all that while, but only that the walles were ſomthing ſtrewed with the fragments of the bullets, that being broken into ſmal peeces, might be ſwee<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ped away with a broome.</p>
            <p>The eighteenth day of Iune being Saturday at night and eleuen of the clocke, they iſſued againe out of the Cittie into our campe, with white linnen ſhirtes ouer their armour: hauing Axes, Demye-pikes, two hande ſwordes, and Dagges, but no peeces at all with them. <hi>Olthof</hi> with his companie hauing drunke well, al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>though he was aduertiſed of their comminge yet made light of it, and feared not the Ene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mies at all: who fell vpon him very furiouſlie and taking him, not making great preparation to withſtand them, ſlewe <hi>Olthof</hi> himſelfe, his lieutenant, his Corporall, and ſome of his Souldiers. But our men hauinge intelligence thereof, ſpeedilie forced them to turne theyr backs and run to their hold.</p>
            <p>Our Lord the <hi>Counte Maurice</hi> cauſed a kinde of warlike engine had in ſuch ca<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>es to be made higher then the Cittie with their loftes, which
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:2117:5" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 117 -->each of them could hold an hundreth menne, inſomuch that no man could by day peepe out of his houſe, but he was ſhot through.</p>
            <p>The tops of all the houſen in the citty were broken downe, and nothing could be ſeen ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cept the ſteeple: and by reaſon that no bodye durſt come into the ſtreets for fear of our ſhot, they broke downe the ſide walles of their houſes and made a paſſage through their hou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes to come by one another, and to take order what ſhould be doone: for they beganne to faint and waxe diſcouraged with the greate loſſe of the people, and the want of powder: and eſpecially bicauſe our men had woon one of their skonſes or fortreſſes, called the halfe moone.</p>
            <p>Within the Citie of <hi>Steenwich</hi> is a great ſquare Market place, which they had ſo ſtrongly for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tified, that the Cittie being taken, yet it would be ſcarce poſſible to driue the enimie out of it without loſſe of men.</p>
            <p>The 24 of Iune there were about two hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred Spaniards, Wallons, and Germans toge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther ſlaine and taken, who were ſent from <hi>Kaeuerden,</hi> each hauing a little bagge of Gun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>powder about his neck, and thinking by ſome ſubtill ſleight to haue entered into the Citie, and in that manner to haue furniſhed it with prouiſion of powder.</p>
            <p>In the end the enemie perceiuing how they
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:2117:6" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 118 -->loſt their Fortreſſes, and ſeeing their forces woonderfully empaired, their prouiſion ſay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling, their ſouldiors ſlaine and wounded, and all the people aſtoniſhed with the miſerie of their preſent eſtate, and terrified with the cala<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitie which they were like to ſuſtayne if they rendered not in time, began to beſeech his ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cellencie to take them to his mercie, promiſing that they would yeeld vp the Citie vpon con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dition that they might ſaue both their life and goods.</p>
            <p>His Excellencie promiſed vnto them, that he would according to the law of warre ſuffer their free ſouldiors to paſſe without any hurte or harme any way done vnto them, but as for the Merchaunts of the Berch and certaine o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Souldiors that had taken oth in <hi>Deuen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter</hi> not to ſerue againſt his Excellencie within three yeares after, thoſe he would in any caſe haue deliuered into his handes to deale with them according to his owne good liking.</p>
            <p>This ſtirred vp a great and ſodaine mutinie in the Citie betweene the ſayd <hi>Deuenter</hi> ſoul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>diers and the Merchaunts of <hi>Berch</hi> againſt the Citizens, ſaieug that they had great wrong of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fered them, conſidering they had aduentured their liues and ſpilt their blood in the behalfe of the citie vpon their promiſe to doe the like for them, and that nowe they woulde in their greateſt neede leaue them, yea giue them vp
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:2117:6" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 118 -->into their enimies hands, and therefore they were reſolued to fight while they could breath againſt the Citizens themſelues, and ſo die in reuenging the iniurie offred them, rather than to ſuffer themſelues to bee hanged by their e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nimies.</p>
            <p>Wherevpon they ſent a drum vnto Count <hi>Maurice</hi> to know of him whether it would not pleaſe his Excellencie to let his mercie bee ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nerally graunted vnto all that were in the Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tie; for that then the woulde without delaye render vp the citie vnto him? which he would not graunt.</p>
            <p>Then our men preſentlye blowed vp the Mine which they had made vnder the earth with gunpowder, which being raiſed on the walles, cauſed many of their Wallon Captains Enſigns &amp; other Souldiors, to flie vp into the Skie as blacke as crowes, which ſo daunted the courage of the enimies, that they preſentlye compounded with Count <hi>Maurice,</hi> and rende<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red the Citie vpon promiſe that their life and goods ſhould be ſaued. In ſo much that his Excellencie tooke them to his mercie, and gaue to them all as well Souldiors as Citizens both life and goods, ſuffering no violence or iniurie to bee offered them by his Souldiors, wherevpon they promiſed that they woulde not ſerue againſt him within ſix moneths after on that ſide of the riuer <hi>Rhyne.</hi> And ſo they paſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:2117:7" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 119 -->with their Rapier and Dagger through out Campe out of the Citie, carrieng whatſoeuer they would with them, and were conducted with his Excellencies Horſſe-men nine miles off, hauing carts and waggins allowed them to conuay away their baggage, and maymed per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons with them. For which merciful and gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle dealing, they all greatly thanked his Excel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lencie. Onely the Merchants of the Berch and <hi>Deuenter</hi> ſouldiors were driue<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> into the church where they ſtoode at his mercie to bee dealt withall as he ſhould thinke good.</p>
            <p>Thus may we thanke almightie God for his great goodneſſe towards vs, in graunting vs ſo great a victorie againſt our enemies, in the enterpriſe vndertaken at the Citie of <hi>Steenewyke.</hi> The 4 day of Iuly 1592.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:2117:7"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 119 -->
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
